Guide to the Gary Cowell photographs, 1959-1961.
Cowell, Gary Cowell photographs, 1959-1961
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Gary Cowell photographs, 1959-1961.
37-5-2370
Gary Kenneth Cowell, 1938-
.4 cubic ft.
78 photoprints; 8 x 10 in.
419 photonegatives; 4 x 5 in.
1051 photoprints; 35 mm.
1051 photonegatives; 35 mm.
Photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Photographs of Cornell campus scenes and activities.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Cornell University Class of 1960. Cornell Daily Sun photographer, 1959-1961.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Photographs of Cornell campus scenes and activities.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cowell, Gary Kenneth, 1938-; Cornell University--Students.; Cornell University--Description--Views.; Cornell University. Class of 1960.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. 4 x 5 film: by subject, undated (ca. 1959-1961)
  - Boardman Hall, 2 (Box 1)
  - Cast Museum, Goldwin Smith Hall, 1 (Box 1)
  - Cayuga Lake, 1 (Box 1)
  - Cayuga Lake Men's Dorms, 1 (Box 1)
  - Class on Quad, 1 (Box 1)
  - Cornell Statue, 1 (Box 1)
  - Fall Creek Gorge, 1 (Box 1)
  - Festival of Contemporary Arts 1960, 1 (Box 1)
  - Fraternity Party, 1 (Box 1)
  - Fuertes Observatory, 1 (Box 1)
  - Fuertes Observatory (Prof. Shaw), 1 (Box 1)
  - Goldwin Smith Hall, 1 (Box 1)
  - Infirmary, 1 (Box 1)
  - Ithaca Restaurant Signs, 1 (Box 1)
  - Louie's Lunchwagon, 1 (Box 1)
  - Orientation, 1 (Box 1)
  - Spectators in the Rain, 1 (Box 1)
  - Student Teaching - Ithaca High School, 1 (Box 1)
  - Tennis, 1 (Box 1)
  - Tray Sliding, 1 (Box 1)
  - White Statue, 1 (Box 1)
  - White Statue and Goldwin Smith Hall, 1 (Box 1)
  - Williard Straight Hall, 1 (Box 1)
- Series II. 4 x 5 film: by date
  - Perkins, Dexter, Oct. 17, 1958; 1 (Box 1)
  - Mills, C. Wright, Nov. 2, 1958; 1 (Box 1)
  - Swimming - Cornell v. Yale, Jan. 10, 1959; 1 (Box 1)
  - Swimming - Cornell v. Army, Feb. 14, 1959; 1 (Box 1)
  - Swimming - Cornell v. Colgate, Feb. 21, 1959; 1 (Box 1)
  - Fall Creek Gorge, Feb. 28, 1959; 1 (Box 1)
  - Voting on Referendum, Mar. 19, 1959; 1 (Box 1)
  - Farm and Home Week, Mar. 26, 1959; 1 (Box 1)
  - Dos Passos, Apr. 29, 1959; 1 (Box 1)
  - Olin Libe Excavation, Apr. 29, 1959; 1 (Box 1)
  - Spring Day, May 1959; 1 (Box 1)
  - Sculpture, May 8, 1959; 1 (Box 1)
  - Apartment Party, May 16, 1959; 1 (Box 1)
  - Hollister Hall Construction, May 19, 1959; 1 (Box 1)
  - Animal Husbandry Building Construction, Sept. 21, 1959; 1 (Box 1)
  - Central Avenue Construction, Sept. 21, 1959; 1 (Box 1)
  - Hollister Hall, Sept. 21, 1959; 1 (Box 1)
  - Hollister Hall Construction, Sept. 21, 1959; 1 (Box 1)
  - Olin Libe Construction, Sept. 21, 1959; 1 (Box 1)
  - Sun Exhibit Activities Fair, Sept. 30, 1959; 1 (Box 1)
  - Football - Cornell v. Lehigh, Band Day, Oct. 3, 1959; 1 (Box 1)
  - Newman Hall - Synchrotron Control Panel, Oct. 8, 1959; 1 (Box 1)
  - Football - Cornell v. Yale, Oct. 17, 1959; 1 (Box 1)
  - Football - Cornell v. Brown, Nov. 1959; 1 (Box 1)
  - Perkins, Dexter, Nov. 4, 1959; 1 (Box 1)
  - Libe North Side Entrance, Nov. 7, 1959; 1 (Box 1)
  - Morrill Hall, Nov. 7, 1959; 1 (Box 1)
  - Schoellkopf and Looking West, Nov. 7, 1959; 1 (Box 1)
  - Football - Cornell v. Dartmouth, Nov. 14, 1959; 1 (Box 1)
  - Space Science Press Conference, Nov. 18, 1959; 1 (Box 1)
  - Sage Chapel, Nov. 20, 1959; 1 (Box 1)
  - Football - Cornell v. Penn, Nov. 23, 1959; 1 (Box 1)
  - State Street, Ithaca, Dec. 1959; 1 (Box 1)
  - Basketball - Cornell v. Bullalo, Dec. 2, 1959; 1 (Box 1)
  - Olin Libe - Gargoyles, Dec. 2, 1959; 2 (Box 1)
  - Basketball - Cornell v. Colgate, Dec. 5, 1959; 1 (Box 1)
  - Dana Grads, Dec. 5, 1959; 1 (Box 1)
  - Basketball - Cornell v. Syracuse, Dec. 8, 1959; 1 (Box 1)
  - Wrestling - Cornell v. Colgate, Dec. 9, 1959; 1 (Box 1)
  - Squash, Jan. 7, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Basketball - Cornell v. Harvard, Jan. 9, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Winter - Cornell, Feb. 16, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Basketball - Cornell v. Yale, Feb. 27, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Pickets - Anti-Segregation, Mar. 1960; 2 (Box 1)
  - Track HEPS - Berlinger, Mar. 1960; 2 (Box 1)
  - Track HEPS - Berlinger, Van Sickle, Mar. 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Track HEPS - Groon, Mar. 1960; 2 (Box 1)
  - Track HEPS - Murray, Mar. 1960; 2 (Box 1)
  - Basketball - Cornell v. Princeton, Mar. 5, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Architect Dragon, Mar. 17, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Olin Libe Construction, Apr. 5, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Cornell Committee Against Segregation, Apr. 26, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Head Stone, Ithaca Cemetery, Apr. 30, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - This Weekend - Al Siegal, May 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - This Weekend - Cindy Ferris, May 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - This Weekend - Jo Anne Stranad, May 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - This Weekend - Liz Kelly, May 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Russians, May 6, 1960; 2 (Box 1)
  - Track - Groon, May 7, 1960; 2 (Box 1)
  - Track Murray, May 7, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Pickets White Art Museum, June 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Olin Libe Construction, July 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Crew - Olympic Trails, Syracuse, July 9, 1960; 2 (Box 1)
  - Treman St. Park, July 15, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Taughannock St. Park, July 20, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Libe Tower, July 27, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Summer School Visitors, July 27, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - ILR School Construction, Aug. 1, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Suspension Bridge, Aug. 1, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Triphammer Bridge, Aug. 1, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Sign "Dead End", Sept. 18, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Football - Varsity Practice, Sept. 20, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Mitchell (Labor Sec.) - Perkins, Frances, Sept. 23, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Accident, Sept. 28, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Football - Cornell v. Harvard (12-0), Oct. 8, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Cascadilla Creek Gorge, Oct. 10, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Cornell University Reactor Facility, Oct. 10, 1960; 2 (Box 1)
  - Football - Cornell v. Yale, Oct. 15, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Rockefeller (NYS Governor), Oct. 18, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Mary Donlon Hall (Women's Dorm), Oct. 21, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Football - Cornell v. Princeton, Oct. 22, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Football - Cornell v. Columbia, Oct. 29, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Sun - Halloween Effigy at Journal, Oct. 31, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Football - Cornell v. Brown, Nov. 5, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Election Democratic H.Q., Auburn, NY, Nov. 8, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Election - John Taber, Auburn, NY, Nov. 8, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Election - Republican H.Q., Auburn, NY, Nov. 8, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Football - Cornell v. Dartmouth, Nov. 12, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Football - Frosh - Cornell v. Penn, Nov. 19, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Daily News Reply, Nov. 20, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Football - Cornell v. Penn, Nov. 24, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Basketball - Cornell v. Colgate, Dec. 3, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Libe Tower, Dec. 6, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Olin Libe, Dec. 6, 1960; 2 (Box 1)
  - Sage ("AG") Chapel, Dec. 6, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Basketball - Cornell v. Bucknell, Dec. 7, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Mens Dorms and Ithaca at Night, Dec. 14, 1960; 1 (Box 1)
  - Veterinary Conference Banquet, Jan. 5, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Veterinary Conference Seminars, Jan. 5, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Basketball - Cornell v. Princeton, Jan. 7, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Olin Libe Exterior at Night, Feb. 8, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Olin Libe Interior, Feb. 8, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Basketball - Cornell v. Dartmouth, Feb. 10, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Basketball - Cornell v. Harvard, Feb. 11, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Basketball - Cornell v. Yale, Feb. 25, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Olin Libe, Feb. 27, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Reactor Facility, Feb. 27, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Olin Libe Exterior at Night, Feb. 28, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Olin Libe, Mar. 3, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Wrestling - Cornell v. Princeton, Mar. 3, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Hockey - Cornell v. Penn, Mar. 4, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Track HEPS, Mar. 4, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Olin Libe at Night, Mar. 15, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Olin Libe Faculty Study, Mar. 15, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Olin Libe Map Room, Mar. 15, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Olin Libe Wason Conference Room, Mar. 15, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Donlon Hall, Mar. 17, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Donlon Hall, Balch Hall, Mar. 17, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Donlon Hall, Dickson Hall, Mar. 17, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Day Hall, Mar. 18, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Globetrotters, Mar. 23, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Olin Libe, Apr. 5, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Baseball - Cornell v. Seton Hall, Apr. 20, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Lacrosse - Cornell v. Colgate, May 3, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Officers Class of '61, May 11, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Crew - Cornell v. Dartmouth v. Detroit Boat Club, May 13, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Spring Day, May 13, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Malott, Deane, June 8, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Weekend, June 10, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Reactor Facility, June 13, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Etchevery Hall Lab 1107, June 19, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Reactor Facility, July 13, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Football - Cornell v. Harvard, Oct. 7, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
- Series III. 35 mm negatives: by date
  - Parents' Weekend - Bar-B-Q, 1959; 1 (Box 1)
  - Boardman Hall Demolition, Mar. 1959; 1 (Box 1)
  - Cayuga Lake from Highway 34, Apr. 1959; 1 (Box 1)
  - Olin Libe - Architects Painting Fence, Apr. 11, 1959; 2 (Box 1)
  - Track, May 9, 1959; 2 (Box 1)
  - Wreck - State St. - Crane and 11 Cars, May 9, 1959; 2 (Box 1)
  - Basketball - Cornell v. Penn, Jan. 4, 1961; 2 (Box 1)
  - Baskettball - Cornell v. Princeton, Jan. 7, 1961; 2 (Box 1)
  - Olin Libe - Sun Tour, Jan. 8, 1961; 2 (Box 1)
  - Students from Los Angeles, Jan. 13, 1961; 2 (Box 1)
  - Olin Libe - Circulation Desk, Feb. 5, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Campus - White Art Museum, Rockefeller Hall, Feb. 7, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Olin Libe - Exterior, Feb. 8, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Olin Libe - Interior, Feb. 8, 1961; 7 (Box 1)
  - Olin Libe - McCarthy, Feb. 8, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Olin Libe - at Night, Feb. 8, 1961; 2 (Box 1)
  - Campus, Feb. 21, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Basketball - Cornell v. Yale, Feb. 25, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Olin Libe - at Night, Feb. 27, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Wrestling - Cornell v. Princeton, Mar. 3, 1961; 8 (Box 1)
  - Wrestling - Cornell v. Penn, Mar. 4, 1961; 5 (Box 1)
  - Track HEPS, Mar. 4, 1961; 11 (Box 1)
  - Fulbright, William, Mar. 6, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Libe Tower, Sage Chapel, Mar. 10, 1961; 2 (Box 1)
  - Olin Libe - at Night, Mar. 15, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Architect's Pranks, Mar. 17, 1961; 5 (Box 1)
  - Sage Chapel, Mar. 19, 1961; 2 (Box 1)
  - Globetrotters, Mar. 23, 1961; 2 (Box 1)
  - Russian Party, Apr. 11, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Winter - Cornell, Apr. 13, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Winter - Ithaca, Apr. 13, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Cuban Issue, Apr. 20, 1961; 5 (Box 1)
  - Lacrosse - Cornell v. Penn, Apr. 26, 1961; 2 (Box 1)
  - Campus, Apr. 27, 1961; 10 (Box 1)
  - Parents Weekend - Band Concert, Apr. 28, 1961; 2 (Box 1)
  - Parents Weekend - Information Desk - Civil Defense Drill Protest (Sane), Apr. 28, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Parents Weekend - Bar-B-Q, Apr. 29, 1961; 2 (Box 1)
  - Parents Weekend - Symposium - Zwingle, Apr. 29, 1961; 2 (Box 1)
  - Crew - Cornell v. Harvard and Rutgers, Apr. 29, 1961; 11 (Box 1)
  - Campus, May 5, 1961; 6 (Box 1)
  - Willard Straight Hall, May 5, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Wreck - State St., Ithaca - Crane and Eleven Cars, May 9, 1961; 1 (Box 1)
  - Campus, May 11, 1961; 3 (Box 1)
  - Campus, May 17, 1961; 4 (Box 1)
  - Russian Party, May 17, 1961; 2 (Box 1)
  - Track - Cornell v. Princeton, May 20, 1961; 12 (Box 1)
  - Baseball - Cornell v. Navy, May 20, 1961; 2 (Box 1)
  - Campus, May 23, 1961; 6 (Box 1)
  - Campus, May 31, 1961; 9 (Box 1)
  - Cornell Alumni Weekend, June 9, 1961; 8 (Box 1)
  - Cornell Alumni Weekend, June 10, 1961; 4 (Box 1)
  - Cornell Alumni Weekend - 1911 Banquet, June 10, 1961; 7 (Box 1)
  - Cornell Senior Week - Class Night, June 11, 1961; 3 (Box 1)
  - Cornell Baccalaureate, June 11, 1961; 5 (Box 1)
  - Cornell Commissioning Ceremony, June 12, 1961; 2 (Box 1)
  - Cornell Graduation, June 12, 1961; 5 (Box 1)
  - Football - Cornell v. Harvard, Oct. 7, 1961; 3 (Box 1)